# Hong Minhee – Résumé

## **Personal Details**

Email hong@minhee.org
Website https://hongminhee.org/
Phone +82 10-3229-7392

# Summary

I first encountered computers and the internet in 1995, and started coding in 2000 when I was in middle school. In 2004, when I was still in high school, I started outsourcing software production on a freelance basis, and have worked as a full-time professional software engineer since 2007. I've contributed to free/open source software since I was a student. I am not only obsessed with technology, but also view software development as work and value teamwork and collaboration. My strengths are that I am good at synthesizing complex situations, and taking conflicting opinions and building consensus, which is what my colleagues often tell about me.

#### **Interests**

- Free/open source softwares: have founded and contributed to many F/OSS projects
- Network programming: implementing asynchronous eventdriven servers and clients
- Domain-specific languages: designing and implementing DSLs
- Functional programming: familiar with immutable data structures, recursions, deterministic functions, abstract data types, and statically typed languages
- Decentralized systems: peer-to-peer networking, Byzantine agreements, and blockchains
- Automated tests: unit tests, property-based tests, and integration tests
- Software internationalization and localization: translation, Unicode, Unicode CLDR, Unicode Han Database, CJK in

general

• Technical writing: writing design papers and documenting legacy code, both in Korean and English

#### Skills

- Languages: Korean (mother tongue), English, Japanese
- Programming languages: Haskell, C#, Python, TypeScript, Bash, SOL
- Platforms: .NET/Mono, Deno
- Databases: PostgreSQL, SQLite, RocksDB
- Et cetera: Linux, Git, Mercurial, Docker

# **Employment**

**2018–2023 Planetarium** Worked on Libplanet, an open source library for creating peer-to-peer multiplayer online games.

Used technologies were: C#, .NET (Core), Mono, NetMQ (ZeroMQ), Unity, and TypeScript.

**2014–2018 Spoqa** Worked on Dodo, a tablet-based customer loyalty and marketing platform for local merchants and stores.

Used technologies were: Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, and PostgreSQL.

**2013 The Beatpacking Company** Worked on Beat, a South Korean music app, which is like Spotify. (Acquired by Naver in 2016.)

Used technologies were: Java (Android), Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, and PostgreSQL.

**2011–2012 StyleShare** StyleShare is a social network service to share fashion photography.

Worked as CTO.

Used technologies were: Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, and PostgreSQL.

**2010 CDNetworks** CDNetworks provides content delivery network service.

Worked on an in-house distributed and scalable monitoring system that manages about 10+ thousand server nodes.

Used technologies were: Python, Tokyo Cabinet, and PostgreSQL.

**2007–2010 Nielsen Korea** Korean branch of Nielsen Company, a global marketing and advertising research company.

Worked on KoreanClick which provides measurement and analysis of online audiences, advertising, video, consumer-generated media, commerce, and consumer behavior.

Worked on Searchian which provides keyword suggestion for search marketing, analysis of keyword advertising platforms, and measurement of keyword usage.

Worked as a substitute of mandatory military service.

Used technologies were: PHP, Pro\*C, Oracle DBMS, and Python.

**2006–2007 Olaworks** Worked on Olalog, a photo sharing social network service based on facial recognition technology.

Retired to do liability for military service.

Used technologies were: Ruby, Rails, and MySQL.

# Mentoring

**2010–2014** Mentor of Software Maestro program by the Ministry of Knowledge Economy, Republic of Korea.

2007, 2008 Mentor of Winter of Code.

### Education

2004-2007 Sunrin Internet High School

#### F/OSS

**2024– Fedify** ActivityPub implementation and federated server framework.

Written in TypeScript (Deno).

2023 – Dojang Cross-platform dotfiles manager.

Written in Haskell.

2018–2023 Libplanet .NET library for creating multiplayer online games in decentralized fashion, which means the whole game play occurs on a peer-to-peer network among equal nodes rather than an authorized central server. Under the hood, it incorporates many features (e.g., digital signature, BFT consensus, data replication) of a blockchain.

Written in C#.

**2016–2018 Nirum** IDL compiler and RPC/distributed object framework for microservices.

Written in Haskell.

**2014–2018 Geofront** Simple SSH key management service which helps to maintain servers to SSH, and authorized\_keys list for them.

Written in Python 3.

2012–2018 libsass-python Sass/SCSS for Python.

Written in C & Python.

**2011–2018 Wand** ctypes-based simple ImageMagick (a widely-used image processing library) binding for Python.

Written in Python.

The above list contains only my representative projects. My more open source activities can be found in my GitHub and Bitbucket.

## **Talks**

- Python and Diaspora: How other languages have influenced Python for 25+ years at PyCon Korea 2017 (keynote)
- Making story of RPC framework (Korean) at PyCon APAC 2016
- All docs lead to Sphinx at SphinxCon JP 2015
- Making story of Geofront: Say goodbye to Python 2 and hello to Python 3 (Korean) at PyCon Korea 2014

The above list contains only the best received ones. My more decks can be found in my Speaker Deck.